Guide to the United States Steel Corporation Duquesne Works Industrial Relations Department Records, 1904-1980 AIS.1987.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United States Steel Corporation Duquesne Works Industrial Relations Department Records
1904-1980
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United States Steel Corporation. Duquesne Works. Department of Industrial Relations
AIS.1987.03
53.75 Linear Feet (43 boxes)
In 1901, the steel mill in Duquesne, Pennsylvania, was included in the purchase of Carnegie Steel by the newly formed United States Steel to become the Duquesne Works, a fully integrated steel making facility. This collection contains records from the Industrial Relations Department of U.S. Steel's Duquesne Works, including employee work history cards and correspondence. Digital reproductions of selected material are available online.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of selected material are available online.
Access Restrictions
Access to the employee cards (Box 3) is restricted for 75 years from date of creation. Until these restrictions are lifted, access to them requires a signed confidentiality agreement. Please contact the Archives Service Center for more information.
Acquisition Information
Gift of USX Realty in 1987 and RIDC Southwestern Pa. Growth Fund in 1991.
History
The Duquesne Steel Mill began in 1886 when a group of Pittsburgh investors built a Bessemer converter shop and blooming mill. In 1888, the mill was purchased by the Allegheny-Bessemer Company, who sold the company to Andrew Carnegie in 1890. Steel made at the plant utilized the open-hearth process and produced rails for the growing railroad industry. In 1901, Duquesne was included in the purchase of Carnegie Steel by the newly formed United States Steel and converted to a fully integrated mill. By 1918, the Duquesne Works had six blast furnaces, thirty-three open-hearth furnaces, and twelve rolling mills. The Steelworkers Organizing Committee and, subsequently, United Steelworkers of America Local 1256 replaced the company representation plan and represented the workers until the mill's closing. In 1969, as demand for their products declined, U.S. Steel merged the National Tube Works with the Duquesne Works to form the National-Duquesne Works. Both plants were downsized in the early 1980s, and the Duquesne plant closed in 1984. Later that year, the "Save Dorothy Six" movement was founded by the Tri-State Conference on Steel to preserve a portion of the Duquesne Works, including its Dorothy Six blast furnace, as a worker-owned business. This plan, however, failed when unforeseen costs for new equipment were discovered and the plant was demolished soon after.
Previous Citation
United States Steel Corporation Duquesne Works Industrial Relations Department Records, 1904-1980, AIS.1987.03, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
United States Steel Corporation National-Duquesne Works Records, 1890-1985, AIS.1991.06, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Elmer J. Maloy Collection, 1916-1989, AIS.2003.05, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains records from the Industrial Relations Department of U.S. Steel's Duquesne Works. Included are employee cards, which provide information on an individual's work history. Grievances and payroll records are also present. Public relations materials and plant security files are included, as well as correspondence regarding a variety of topics.
Labor; Business and Industry; Iron and steel workers -- Pennsylvania -- Duquesne; Steel industry and trade -- Pennsylvania -- Duquesne; Payroll records; Business records; Office files; Minutes (Administrative records); Ledgers (Account books); Duquesne (Pa.); Iron and steel workers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Duquesne; United States Steel Corporation. Duquesne Works; United States Steel Corporation. Duquesne Works. Department of Industrial Relations; Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation; Carnegie Steel Company; United Steelworkers of America. Local 1256 (Duquesne, Pa.)
- Payroll, 1904-1940 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 1-41)
- Third Step Minutes, 1946-1950, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
- Various Blast Furnace Reline Data, 1962-1964, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Appropriate Requests and Data, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Grievance Committee Minutes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Seniority and Continued Service, 1938-1939, 1943-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Promotional Sequence, 1943-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Service Awards, 1937, 1942-1947, 1949-1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Agreement on and Job Descriptions and Classifications of Plant-Wide Labor Pool, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Seniority Agreements, All CIS Plants, 1945-1949, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Blooming Mills, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Conditioning, 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Thefts of Company Property, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Thefts of Employee Property, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Blast Furnace, 1946-1950, 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Seniority Unit Agreements, 1947-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Force Reduction, Part Timing and Furloughing During Curtailed Operations, 1937-1942, 1949-1950, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Force Reductions, 1949-1952, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- An Applied Citizenship Publication on Political Party Structure, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Guide Book on Political Party Structure, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Employee Cards [RESTRICTED] (Box 3)
- Working Schedules, 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Schedules, General Correspondence, 1936-1953 (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
- Housekeeping Tours, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Health and Sanitation, 1941-1957 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Safety, General Correspondence, 1938-1953 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- Third Step Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
- Agreements, 1958, 1963, 1965, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Booklets, 1958-1966 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
- Incentive Correspondence, 1950-1960 (Box 6, Folder 1-8)
- Vacations, 1936-1953 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
- Wages, General Correspondence, 1933-1946 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Payment for Meetings, Training Courses and Volunteer Firemen, 1943-1955 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Mold Yard Notebooks, July 18-November 14, 1980 (Box 6, Item 1-2)
- Individual Grievances, 1957-1958 (Box 7)
- Section 2B Local Working Conditions, 1953, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Grievance Procedure and Correspondence, 1937-1959 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Individual Relations Reports, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Noncontributory Pension Plan, 1937-1959 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Contributory Pension Plan, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Pensions, 1957-1968 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
- Employment and Recruiting, 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Licenses, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Military Services, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Fair Labor Standards Act, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Labor Legislation, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- 1950 Social Security Act, 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Labor Legislation, Unemployment Compensation, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Labor Relations, 1943-1957 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- General Correspondence, 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Organization and Functions, Industrial Relations Department, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Engineering Department, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- General Operating, 1958-1964 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Hospital, 1957-1963 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Industrial Recreations and Employee Activities, 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Industrial Relations, Promotions and Transfers, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Insurance Benefit Plans, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Group Insurance Plan, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Benefit and Relief Organizations, 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Insurance, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Major Medical Expenses Insurance for Eligible Nonexempt Salaried Employees, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Terminations, Leaves of Absence, and Transfers, 1935-1955 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Discipline Reports, 1944-1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Disciplinary Actions, 1938-1957 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Employee Identification, 1940-1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Physical Examinations, 1938-1957 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Citizenship, Aliens and Subversives, 1939-1955 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Merit Ratings, 1936-1943 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Duquesne Golden Jubilee, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Public Relations, 1937-1952, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
- Procedure for Handling Inquiries from Outside Sources, 1939-1957 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Damage to Property, 1937-1956 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1950-1956 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Housing, 1936, 1939, 1942-1947 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Sale of Material to Employees, 1936, 1938, 1948-1954 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Civic Organizations, 1936-1957 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Wage Rate Inequities, 1945-1957 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- Overtime Pay, 1936-1957 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Shift Differences, 1945-1951 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Salary Inequities Program, 1947-1956 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Severence Allowances, 1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Supplemental Unemployment Benefits, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Welfare, 1935-1954 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Individual Grievances, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 9-69)
- Individual Grievances, Local 1256, 1941-1944 (Box 11)
- Open Hearth, Pay Sarah Cash for Time Lost due to Termination, March 22, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Compensation Worksheets, 1945-1959 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Contracting out Notices, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Administrative Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Evaluation Statements, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Contracting Out Notifications to Union, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Workmens Standard Time Book, August 1960-October 1962 (Box 12, Item 1)
- Job Description and Classification Manual, 1953 (Box 12, Item 2)
- Salary Rate Inequities Agreement between Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation and the United Steelworkers of America, May 6, 1950 (Box 12, Item 3)
- Eligibility List for Union Shop Election, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Third Step Minutes, 1951, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
- Work Stopage Reports, 1942-1953 (Box 13, Folder 4-7)
- Work Stoppage and Strike Clippings, 1946-1952 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Exempt Salary Attendance Reports, 1965 (Box 14, Item 1)
- Injury Reports, 1949-1962 (Box 14, Item 2)
- Carnegie Steel Time Book, 1919 (Box 14, Item 3)
- Principles of Accident Prevention at US Steel, 1959 (Box 15, Volume 1)
- Local Working Conditions, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Agenda for Labor Relations Meeting, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Seniority Agreement between US Steel Corp. and United Steelworkers of America, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Personnel, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Appointments and Promotions, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Terminations and Transfers, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Discipline Reports, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Disciplinary Actions, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Employee Identification, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Physical Exams, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Citizenship and Aliens, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- College Recruiting, 1960-1962 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Open House (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Safety Contracts, 1959-1961 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Safety, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Health and Sanitation, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Safety Committees, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Joint Safety Committee, 1947-1961 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Schedules, 1957-1961 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Holiday Schedules, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Contract Schedule Negotiations, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Seniority and Continuous Service, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Seniority Unit Agreements, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 23)
- Plant Wide Seniority Agreement, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Individual Grievances, 1953 (Box 16)
- Strike Files, 1947-1961 (Box 17)
- Individual Grievances, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 1-46)
- Blooming Mills, 1944-1956 (Box 18, Folder 47)
- Electric Furnace, 1941-1957 (Box 18, Folder 48)
- Engineering Department, 1951-1957 (Box 18, Folder 49)
- General Operating, 1952-1956 (Box 18, Folder 50)
- General Service and Transportation, 1947-1955 (Box 18, Folder 51)
- Hospital, 1937-1957 (Box 18, Folder 52)
- Maintenance Department, 1934-1957 (Box 18, Folder 53-54)
- Open Hearth, 1963-1966 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Duquesne News for Supervisors, 1961-1963 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Engineering Department, 1956-1960 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Maintenance Division, 1958-1960 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Masonary, 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Outside Sources, 1958-1961 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Other US Steel Subsidiaries, 1958-1961 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Plant Protection, 1959-1966 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Expense Allowance, 1959-1961 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Fire, 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Plant Protection, 1960-1966 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Primary Mills, 1959-1961 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Production Planning, 1950-1963 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Metallurgical Department, 1950-1952 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- City Office Correspondence, 1960-1966 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Industrial Relations, 1961-1966 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Individual Grievances, Local 1256, 1945-1949 (Box 20)
- Excluded Positions from 1941 Agreements, NLRB Election, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- NLRB Elections, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
- Time Records, 1951-1960 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Third Step Minutes, 1952-1955, 1957, 1959-1960 (Box 22)
- Individual Grievances, 1960-1965 (Box 23, Folder 1-34)
- Engineering Department, Contracting Out, 1967-1971 (Box 23, Folder 35-38)
- Personnel Services Evaluation Statements, 1966-1971 (Box 23, Folder 39-40)
- Individual Grievances, 1934-1941 (Box 24)
- Third Step Minutes, 1937-1943, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
- Wages, 1947-1952 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Incentives, 1939-1950 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Paydays and Advances, 1935-1957 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Wage Rate Inequities, 1945-1957 (Box 25, Folder 6-8)
- Progress Report on Wage Rate Inequity Negotiations by the United Steelworkers of America, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Fair Days Work Policies and Procedures, June 30, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Inequities Program, Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation and the United Steelworkers of America, 1945-1947 (Box 25, Folder 1-7)
- Strikes (Box 26, Folder 1)
- College Recruiting, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Strike Reports, 1944-1945, 1948-1952 (Box 26, Folder 3-4)
- Supervision, 1937-1949 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Suggestion Awards, 1950s (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Suggestions, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Saving Fund Plan, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Supplemental Unemployment Benefits, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Taxes, 1945-1957 (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Federal Income and Withholding Tax, 1937, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- Theft of Employees, 1937, 1943-1944 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- Theft of Company, 1937-1948 (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Packet for US Steel Families Moving to Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Booklets, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Duquesne Works United States Steel, c. 1960; 1.
- Bulletin Boards, General Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Contributions and Dues Budget, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Duquesne Works News for Supervisors, 1957-1965 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Budget, 1958-1961 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Posters and Notices, 1960-1964 (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Duquesne Works Budget, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 8)
- United Foods Cafeteria, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Cafeteria, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 10)
- Individual Clubs, 1963-1967 (Box 27, Folder 11-15)
- Conferences, 1959-1963 (Box 27, Folder 16)
- Christmas Cards and Decorations, 1965-1967 (Box 27, Folder 17)
- All Departments, 1958-1963 (Box 27, Folder 18)
- Accounting Department, 1958-1961, 1964-1966 (Box 27, Folder 19-20)
- Engineering Department, 1958-1966 (Box 27, Folder 21)
- Maintenance of Membership, 1936-1966 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
- Union Shop Elections, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 3)
- United Steelworkers Local Union Notices, 1939-1969 (Box 28, Folder 4)
- United Steelworkers Local 1256 General Correspondence, 1937-1969 (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
- United Steelworkers Locals 1256, 2466, and 3033 Correspondence, 1944-1969 (Box 28, Folder 7)
- Positions Excluded from Membership, 1942-1952 (Box 28, Folder 8)
- Your Union Slater Publication, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 9)
- Local 1256 Officers and Committeemen, 1937-1967 (Box 28, Folder 10-12)
- Individual Grievances, 1956-1957 (Box 29)
- Unemployment Compensation Cases, Union Railroad Strike, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Accounting (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Bar Mills, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Electric Furnace, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Promotional Sequence, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Holiday Schedule, 1945-1955 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Schedule Survey, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Supervision, 1958-1961 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Suggestion Awards, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Suggestions, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Savings Correspondence, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 11)
- Supplemental Unemployment Agreement, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- General Tax Correspondence, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Federal Income and Withholding Tax, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Social Security, 1959-1961 (Box 30, Folder 15)
- Unemployment Compensation, 1958-1960 (Box 30, Folder 16)
- Training and Education, 1961-1962 (Box 30, Folder 17)
- Vacations, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 18)
- Wages, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 19)
- Payment for Meeting, 1957-1960 (Box 30, Folder 20)
- Incentives, 1954-1960 (Box 30, Folder 21)
- Paydays, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 22)
- Wage Rate Inequities, 1958-1960 (Box 30, Folder 23)
- Job Classification Negotiations, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 24)
- Overtime Pay, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 25)
- Severance Allowances, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 26)
- Women, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 27)
- Women, General Correspondence, 1937-1957 (Box 30, Folder 28)
- Third Step Minutes, 1944-1945, 1965-1967 (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
- Local Issues, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Funeral Leaves, 1977-1979 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- General Discussion Items on 3rd Step Minutes, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Engineering Department, 1951-1956 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Force Reductions, 1960-1961 (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
- NLRB Strike Vote, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 10)
- Job Description, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 11)
- Working Force, 1961-1963 (Box 31, Folder 12-16)
- Seniority, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 17)
- Safety and Health, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 18)
- Local Work Conditions, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 19-20)
- Christmas Cards, 1950-1952 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Releases for Use of Photographs and Names, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Duquesne Carnegie Library, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Duquesne Plant Protection Case, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 4)
- Portal to Portal Pay Suits, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
- Safety, 1958-1960 (Box 32, Folder 7)
- To Be Filed, 1955-1957 (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Industrial Engineering (Box 32, Folder 9-13)
- Internal Security (Box 32, Folder 14)
- Defense Preperations (Box 32, Folder 15)
- Junior Achievement, 1958-1961 (Box 32, Folder 16)
- Press Visit, United States Steel's Duquesne Works Oxygen Plant, June 12, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 17)
- Duquesne, New Mill, 1957-1961 (Box 32, Folder 18)
- Press Releases, New Metallurgy Lab, 1958 (Box 32, Folder 19)
- Vacuum Casting Clippings, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 20)
- Duquesne Works Operations (Box 32, Folder 21)
- Plant Variance and Capacity Reports (Box 32, Folder 22)
- Maps of Duquesne Works (Box 32, Folder 23)
- Automobile Passes, Traffic Hazards, Violations and Surveys (Box 33, Folder 1)
- Procedure for Handling Inquiries from Outside Sources, 1958-1961 (Box 33, Folder 2)
- Damage to Property (Box 33, Folder 3)
- General Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Plant Visits (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh Area Plants: Visit of Board of Directors, October 15-17, 1958; 1.
  - Duquesne Works Welcomes You To Its New Oxygen Steel Producing Shop, c. 1964; 2.
  - "Dorothy" Blast Furnace, c. 1963; 3.
- Press Visit, Oxygen Steelmaking Department Duquesne Works, May 14, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Press Visit, Oxygen Steelmaking Department Duquesne Works, May 14, 1964
- Relighting No.2 Blast Furnace, Duquesne Works Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation, May 25, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 7)
- United States Steel Corporation Engineering Committee Visit to Duquesne Works, May 8, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 8)
- American Iron and Steel Institute Manufacturing Problems Committee Visit to Homestead and Duquesne Works, March 18, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 9)
- Open House Plant Visits (Box 33, Folder 10)
- Permits to Take Pictures (Box 33, Folder 11)
- Releases for Use of Photographs and Names (Box 33, Folder 12)
- Plant Gas Program (Box 33, Folder 13)
- Community Fund, Red Cross and Salvation Army (Box 33, Folder 14-15)
- Solicitations, 1958-1961 (Box 33, Folder 16-17)
- United States Bonds (Box 33, Folder 18-19)
- Supervision, 1950-1953 (Box 33, Folder 20)
- Training and Education, 1944-1953 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
- US Steel Subsidiaries (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - 525: The new home of United States Steel, c. 1952; 1.
  - Robena Mine: H.C. Frick Coke Company, Formal opening, September 12, 1946; 2.
- General Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 4)
- USS News Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 5-6)
- USS News (Box 34, Folder 7-8)
- USS Radio and Television Shows (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
- USS Quarterly (Box 34, Folder 11-12)
- Plan for Proposed Ramp and Overhead Crossing, Oliver Avenue Mill Entrance, Lower Works, February 23, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 13)
- Employee Cards (Box 35-43)
- Civic Organizations (Box 44, Folder 1)
- Community Day at Duquesne Works, October 1936 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Community Day: Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation Duquesne Steel Works, October 23, 1936; 1.
- Duquesne Golden Jubilee, September 1941 (Box 44, Folder 3)
- Plant Visits (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - "Welcome to Duquense Works", December 1957; 1.
- Open House Day at Duquesne Works, September 19, 1942 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Open House at Clairton Works, September 19, 1946; 1.
  - Tour of Johnstown Lorain Works, Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation, c. 1946; 2.
- Open House Plant Visits, Duquesne Works (Box 44, Folder 6)
- Open House Plant Visits, Other Plants (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - "Steel!", 1956; 1.
  - Pennsylvania Week Open House: Donora Steel & Wire Works, American Steel & Wire Company, September 30, 1948; 2.
  - Inspection Trip Homestead Steel Tours, 3.
  - "ARMCO: 20 Years in Butler", September 1947; 4.
  - Edgar Thomson Works 1873-1936: Public Viewing Days for the Tri-Boro Community, October 19-21, 1936; 5.
  - Edgar Thomson Works, c. 1940; 6.
  - Edgar Thomson Works Open House as a Part of Pennsylvania Week, September 19, 1946; 7.
  - Guide Manual: Irvin Works, Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation, 8.
  - Your visit to Irvin Works, 9.
  - Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Company Visitors Service Bureau, 10.